Welcome back. In this video we're gonna begin our discussion of semantic analysis
欢迎回来。在这段视频中，我们将开始讨论语义分析
with the topic of scope. The motivating problem for talking about scope is that we
以范围为主题。谈论范围的动机问题是我们
want to be able to match identifier declarations with the uses of those
我希望能够将标识符声明与这些声明的使用相匹配
identifiers. We need to know which variable we're talking about when we see
标识符。我们需要知道当我们看到
variable X if variable X might have more than one definition in the program. And
如果变量X在程序中可能有多个定义，则为变量X。和
this is an important aesthetic analysis step in most programming languages,
这是大多数编程语言中重要的美学分析步骤，
including, [inaudible]. So here are a couple of examples taken from cool. This
包括，[听不见]。这里有几个取自COOL的例子。这
definition Y, this declaration Y that it's a string will be matched with this used
定义Y，此声明Y表示它是一个字符串，将与此使用的
and so we'll know at this point here that Y is supposed to be a string and you'll
所以我们现在就知道Y应该是一根弦，你会
get some kind of an air for a compiler because you're trying to add a string and
为编译器获得某种形式的空气，因为您正在尝试添加一个字符串，并且
a number. In the second example Here's a declaration of Y And then in the body of
一个数字。在第二个示例中，这里是Y的声明，然后在
the [inaudible] we, we don't see any use of Y And that, by itself is not an error.
[听不见的]我们，我们看不到Y的任何用处，这本身并不是一个错误。
It's perfectly fine to declare a variable that you don't use. Although you could
声明一个不使用的变量完全可以。尽管你可以
imagine generating a warning for that, that doesn't actually cause the program to
想象一下为此生成警告，这实际上不会导致程序
behave badly, But instead what we see here is a use of X and there's no matching
行为不佳，但我们在这里看到的是X的使用，没有匹配
definitions. So the question is where is the definition of X? We can't see it And
定义。所以问题是X的定义在哪里？我们看不到它，而且
if there is no outer definition of X then we'll get and undefined or undeclared
如果没有X的外部定义，那么我们将获取未定义或未声明的
variable error here at this point. So these two examples illustrate the idea of
此时此处出现变量错误。这两个例子说明了
scope. The scope of an identifier is that portion of a program in which the
范围。标识符的作用域是程序中
identifier is accessible. And just know that the same identifier may refer to
标识符是可访问的。并且只知道相同的标识符可能指的是
different things and different parts of the program. And different scopes for the
不同的东西和节目的不同部分。和不同的作用域
same name can't overlap. So whenever the variable x, for example, means, it can
同名不能重叠。所以无论何时变量x，例如，意味着，它可以
only refer to one thing in an given part of the program. And identifiers can have
在程序的给定部分中只引用一件事。并且标识符可以具有
restricted scope. There are lots of examples, I'm sure you're familiar with
受限制的范围。有很多例子，我相信你一定很熟悉
them, of identifiers whose scope is less than the entire program. Most programming
它们是指范围小于整个程序的标识符。大多数编程
languages today have what is called static s cope. And cool is an example of a
今天的语言有所谓的静电的应对方式。而Cool就是一个例子，
statically scoped language. The characteristic of static scoping is that
静态作用域语言。静电作用域的特点是
the scope of the variable depends only on the program text, not on any kind of
变量的作用域仅取决于程序文本，而不取决于任何类型的
runtime behavior. So what the program actually does at runtime doesn't matter.
运行时行为。所以程序在运行时实际做什么并不重要。
The scope is defined purely syntactically from the way you wrote the program. Now it
作用域完全是根据您编写程序的方式从语法上定义的。现在它
may come as a surprise that there is any alternative to static scoping. In fact,
除了静电作用域之外，还有任何其他选择，这可能会让人感到惊讶。事实上,
probably every language that you have used up to now has had static scoping But there
到目前为止，您使用的每种语言可能都有静电作用域，但是
are a few languages that are, what are called, dynamically scoped. And for a long
有几种语言，也就是所谓的动态作用域。在很长一段时间里
time actually there was an argument about whether static scoping was better than
事实上，关于静电作用域是否比
dynamic scoping. Although today, I think, it is pretty clear that static scoping
动态作用域。虽然今天，我认为，很明显，静电作用域
camp has, has won this discussion But historically, at least, LISP was an
坎普赢得了这场讨论，但至少从历史上看，LISP是一种
example of a dynamically scoped language. And it has switched, in the meantime. This
动态作用域语言的示例。与此同时，它已经发生了变化。这
is actually a long time ago now that it changed, to static scoping. Another
其实已经是很久以前的事了，现在改成了静电作用域。另一个
language which is now mostly of historical interest, it isn't really used anymore,
现在最具历史价值的语言，现在已经不再使用了，
called Snowball, also had, dynamic scoping. And the characteristic of dynamic
叫雪球，也有，动态范围。以及动态性的特点
scoping is that the scope of a variable depends on the execution behavior of the
作用域是指变量的作用域取决于
program. So let's take a look at an example of [inaudible]. So, here we have
程序。那么让我们来看一个[听不见]的例子。所以，我们这里有
some [inaudible] code, and, a couple of different declarations of X, and also,
一些[听不见的]代码，几个不同的X声明，还有，
some different uses of X. Let me erase these. [inaudible] underline so I can use
X的一些不同用法。让我把它们擦掉。[听不见]下划线以便我可以使用
the color to indicate, binding. So, let's take a look at this definition. The
要指示的颜色，绑定。那么，让我们来看看这个定义。这个
question is which of these uses of x, we have three uses of x, actually refer to
问题是，在x的这些用法中，我们有三种用法，实际上指的是x的哪三种用法
that definition. So, it is, in fact, these two, the ones that are outside of the
这个定义。所以，实际上是这两个，在宇宙之外的那两个
inner let. These actually refer to this definition. So, here if you refer to x,
内部信封。这些实际上指的是这个定义。所以，在这里，如果你指的是x，
you get the value zero But, this other definition here. The inner definition of
你得到的值是0，但是，这里有另一个定义。的内在定义
x, is, is used by this use of x. So this use of x, gets this va-, this meaning of
x，is，由x的这个用法使用。所以x的这个用法得到这个va-，这个意思是
x, which in this case, returns the value one. And what's going on here is that
X，在本例中，它返回值1。这里发生的事情是
we're using the most closely, what's called the most closely nested rule. So a
我们使用的是最紧密的，也就是所谓的最紧密嵌套的规则。所以一个
variable binds to the definition that is most closely enclosing it of the same
变量绑定到与其最接近的定义
name. So this x the closest enclosing definition of x is this one, but for these
名字。所以这个x最接近的封闭定义是这个，但是对于这些
two x's, the closest and only enclosing definition of x is this outer one. So in
两个x，最接近也是唯一封闭的x的定义是这个外层的。所以在
dynamically scoped language, a variable would refer to the closest binding in the
动态作用域语言中，变量将引用
execution of the program, meaning the most recent binding of the variables, so here's
程序的执行，这意味着变量的最新绑定，所以这里是
an example, let's say we have a function G, and G defines a variable A, and here's
举个例子，假设我们有一个函数G，G定义了一个变量A，这里是
it initialized say to four, and then it calls another function Another function
它将比方说初始化为4，然后调用另一个函数另一个函数
that isn't in the same syntactic scope. So here I've written F right next to G but
这不在相同的句法范围内。所以这里我在G旁边写了F，但是
actually F could be in some completely other part of the code and F refers to A.
实际上，F可能在代码的某个完全不同的部分，而F指的是A。
And the question is, what is the value of A here? Well. If it's if we dynamically
问题是，这里A的值是多少？井。如果我们动态地
scoped then it's going to be the value that was defined in G and here F of X will
作用域，那么它将是在G中定义的值，这里X的F将
actually return four, that will be the result of this call because this reference
实际返回4，这将是此调用的结果，因为此引用
to A. We'll refer to this binding or this definition of A and G. And, we can't say
A，我们将引用这个约束或A和G的这个定义，而且我们不能说
much more about how dynamics, how dynamics scope works until we talk in a little more
更多关于动力学是如何工作的，动力学范围是如何工作的，直到我们更深入地讨论
detail about how languages are implemented. So we'll talk about dynamic
有关语言如何实现的详细信息。所以我们将讨论动态
scope again a little later on in the course. In Cool, identifier bindings are
本课程稍后再讲一遍。在Cool中，标识符绑定是
introduced by a variety of mechanisms. Now there are class declarations, which
由多种机制引入。现在有了类声明，其中
introduce class names. Method definitions, which introduce method names, And then
介绍类名。方法定义，它引入方法名称，然后
there is several different ways to introduce object, object identifiers. And
有几种不同的方式来引入对象，对象标识符。和
these are the [inaudible] expressions, [inaudible] parameters of functions,
这些是[听不见的]表达式、[听不见的]函数参数、
attribute definitions in classes, and finally in the branches of case
类中的属性定义，最后是Case分支中的属性定义
expressions. It's important to understand that not all identifiers follow the most
表情。重要的是要了解，并不是所有的标识符都遵循最多
closely nested rule that we outlined before. So for example a rather, rather
我们之前概述的紧密嵌套规则。所以举个例子来说，相当，相当
large exception to this rule is class definitions in Cool. So class definitions
此规则的最大例外是Cool中的类定义。所以类定义
cannot be nested. And in fact they are globally visibl e throughout the program.
不能嵌套。事实上，它们在整个计划中都是全球可见的。
And what does that mean? That means that a class name is defined everywhere If it's
那是什么意思？这意味着在任何地方都会定义一个类名，如果它是
defined anywhere in the program, that class name is available for use anywhere
在程序中的任何位置定义，该类名都可以在任何地方使用
in the program or everywhere in the program. And in particular, a class name
在程序中或程序中的任何地方。尤其是类名
can be used before it is defined. So as an example, take a look at this fragment of
可以在定义它之前使用。因此，作为一个示例，请看一下以下片段
cool code here. And here we see that in class foo, we declare y to be of type var
这里的代码很酷。在这里我们可以看到，在类foo中，我们将y声明为var类型
and then later on we declare class var. This is perfectly fine cool code. The fact
然后稍后我们声明class var。这是非常好的很酷的代码。事实是
that var is used before it is defined has no effect on whether the program is
在定义变量之前使用该变量不会影响程序是否
correct. This is a completely legal cool code Similarly with attribute names.
对，是这样。这是一个完全合法的很酷的代码，与属性名称类似。
Attribute names are global within the class in which they are defined, so, I,
属性名称在定义它们的类中是全局的，因此，i
that means they can be used again before they are defined. So for example, I can
这意味着在定义它们之前可以再次使用它们。例如，我可以
define a class foo, and I can define a method that uses attribute a, and then
定义一个类foo，我可以定义一个使用属性a的方法，然后
later on, only later on, do I define what attribute a is, and that is perfectly
稍后，只有稍后，我才定义属性a是什么，这是非常完美的
legal. So normally The list attribute definitions before method definitions, but
合法的。所以通常列表属性定义在方法定义之前，但是
that's not required. A actually the method and attributory definitions can come in
这不是必须的。A实际上方法和属性定义可以在
any order we like, within a class, and in-particular an attribute can be used
可以在类中使用我们喜欢的任何顺序，尤其是属性
before it is defined. Finally method names have quite complex rules. For example, a
在定义它之前。最后，方法名称有相当复杂的规则。例如，一个
method doesn't have to be defined in the class in which it is used. It could just
方法不必在使用它的类中定义。它可能只是
be defined in some pairing class. And also methods can be redefined. So it's possible
在某个配对类中定义。而且还可以重新定义方法。所以有可能
to what's called overwriting of a method and give a method a new definition Even
所谓的方法重写，甚至给方法一个新的定义
though it has been defined before. We don't actually have the language yet to
虽然它以前已经被定义过了。我们实际上还没有相应的语言
talk about these rules with any precision but we'll be going into this in future videos.
请尽可能精确地谈论这些规则，但我们将在未来的视频中对此进行深入探讨。